When people find out about shadow the hedgehog
they usually react with, "what the hell were they thinking?"
but that's the thing, they were thinking
but you weren't smart enough to get it
I know, Kilian Experience with another silly video
This time I speak with passion
about a game that shaped an industry
It was 2005 when I first saw Shadow the Hedgehog
at gamestop.
No,
at a non copyrighted store.
I knew it was adult and raw,
a bit too much for my child mind.
So instead I bought chaos theory
much more suited for children
Years passed and I finally finished reading "War and Peace."
No, not the book
the gay sonic fanfiction.
It made me understand that this character might be more than just an edgy hedgehog
So I bought it with the intention of making a clickbait review
As opposed to other Shadow the Hedgehog games
in this one you only play as him
You don't have to waste time as a blue ripoff
As you play, you get to pick between two sides
Either be good
or be edgy
Maxing out the good bar lets you skip the map
Why would you skip your perfection?
You are misunderstanding. It's a statement that
doing good things might lead to negative consequences
but ofcourse, let's talk about the best thing in the game
When I played classic sonic, I always thought this game could really use
assault rifles
It throws some people off
It was an attempt to appeal more to a western audience
And I have to say, I feel pretty appealed to.
The first level is even called "Westopolis"
I'm so represented
The music is
.
..
...
euphoric
and lets me fulfill my dream of becoming an angsty teenager
Let's talk about the elephant in the room
Shadow
does not look like a
hedgehog
I don't know why
Maybe the gamecube wasn't powerful enough
Maybe sega couldn't get the rights to hedgehogs from god or something.
For whatever reason, it's my biggest gripe with the game
The rest of the visuals are pure art
Remember those gibly movies or hand drawn Disney?
Well, STH is about to make them look like a sewage plant
The story is a tail as old as time
A hedgehog has nothing but a vague memory of the government killing his friend
and then aliens attack
The alien leader wants to ally with Shadow
and he agrees for no reason.
But also a human general hates him for some secret reason
But the president has a framed photo of them
Him and the CIA love hedgehogs
But none of this matters because they give up on both of these plots in the middle of the story
Because Shadow thinks he might be a robot
"Oh no"
A hedgebot.
Finishing the main story clears up literally nothing
But don't worry there are 9 other endings
All of them g--
All of them endings
What's brilliant about it is that it takes all of these overused plots
and does them all at the same time
Creating something that could only have be done by a lunati--
Done by a genuis
There is also political commentary
Oviously pointing out the US government's over reliance on super fast hedgehogs
but also less obvious stuff, like they call the aliens
"The black aliens"
But they are not black. That makes you think, huh?
about
Prejuice
And the humanity
When shadow came out, it recieved mixed reviews
But here we are 12 years later, still talking about it
and I think we still will after another 12 years
So, lets answer the question
Is Shadow the Hedgehog a treasure basically crafted by the old renessaince masters?
Well this reviewer...
says No!
NO!
It's Shadow the Hedgehog, it's trash
Dumbass
*Sonicboom themesong*